

MUHAMMAD RAHEEL ANWAR

Address: H-12 Sector, NUST Univeristy, Islamabad, Pakistan

Phone: +92 302 980 2838 **Email:** pingmra@gmail.com

Portfolio: www.github.com/raheelism

SUMMARY

Accomplished software developer specializing in mobile application development with Flutter using GetX, Provider, bloc and clean code pattern. I have successfully developed over 25+ mobile apps for clients and 30+ open souce contribution. Also contributed to more than 25 machine learning projects. Currently engaged in advanced research on large language models (Mixture of Agent), demonstrating a deep commitment to cutting-edge technology.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Software Engineer, Inshort Tech - UK (Remote - Full time)

Feb 2022 - Present

- · Worked as Mobile Application Developer using Flutter
- Developed 7+ Mobile Application including inshort quiz, scholarly, saaz, vidown and more.

Researcher, Capble IZBA - USA (Remote - Part time)

Sept 2022 - Jan 2024

- Worked as researcher for Fulfillment Centers Data all over the world
- Developed scrapping scripts, Al models for data cleaning, optimization and automation

Lecturer, NFCIET University - Multan - (Visiting)

Sept 2020 - Sept 2022

Worked as lecturer for Mobile Development and Game Development

Software Developer, Xufire Tech - Multan - (On Site - Full time)

Dec 2020 - Aug 2021

- Worked as Mobile Application Developer using Flutter
- Developed 3+ Mobile Application including Complyform, Cosmos Redshift, PropertyX and more

Software Developer, InfoTech4IT - Lahore - (Hybrid - Full time)

Jun 2019 - Jul 2020

- Worked as Mobile Application Developer using Flutter
- Developed 3+ Mobile Application including Complyform, Cosmos Redshift, PropertyX and more

EDUCATION

MS Computer Science - NUST Islamabad

Aug 2022 - Present

Engineering University

- Major in Artificial Intelligence ML DL and Generative Al.
- Thesis on "MCQs generation using Large Language Models".

BS Computer Science - NFC IET Multan

Aug 2016 - Sep 2020

Engineering University

 Final year project in "Shopping Store Mobile Application using Flutter" and "Belivers - HDRP Game Development using Unity3D"

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

- Technical Skills: Flutter Mobile Application Developemt, Python ML, DL and LLMs, Android, Unity3D, Adobe XD, Figma and SEM
- Languages: English, Urdu
- Certifications: 20+ Professional Certifications from Coursera, Udemy and Udacity
- Awards/Activities: 20+ Badges from IBM, ICE 2018 Winner

Cashew - Flutter

Managing finances effectively - with Drift's SQL package, and Firebase https://github.com/raheelism/Cashew

PixEz - Flutter

A third-party client for pixiv written in Flutter. https://github.com/raheelism/flutter-pixiv

PiliPala - Flutter

BiliBili third-party client developed using Flutter https://github.com/raheelism/flutter-video-streaming-app

E-Commerce App - Flutter

The Shop template for e-commerce app https://github.com/raheelism/e-commerce-flutter-app

Flet - Framework

Flet build realtime web, mobile and desktop apps https://github.com/raheelism/flet

Flutter Boilerplate - Template

A boilerplate code for flutter apps with all configs https://github.com/raheelism/flutter-boilerplate

Flutter bloc - Template

Basic functions of intl, theme peeling etc. https://github.com/raheelism/flutter_bloc_app_template

Flutter streaming Music

A cross platform App for streaming Music app https://github.com/raheelism/flutter-samples

Whatsapp clone - Flutter

Flutter WhatsClone (Firebase + Clean Architecture) https://github.com/raheelism/whatsApp_clone

Harmony Music - Flutter

A cross platform app for music streaming made with Flutter(Android, Windows, linux). https://github.com/raheelism/flutter-streaming-music

Spotify Clone - Flutter

A spotify clone developed in flutter using flutter bloc https://github.com/raheelism/Flutter-Spotify

Douban - Flutter

Douban third-party client developed using Flutter https://github.com/raheelism/FlutterDouBan

Noa - Flutter

Noa is Al assistant to run on your Frame AR glasses https://github.com/raheelism/noa-flutter

Open source Flutter Apps Resource

A list of open source flutter applications https://github.com/raheelism/open-source-flutter-apps

Prompt Engineering Guide

Guides, papers, lecture, notebooks and resources https://github.com/raheelism/Prompt-Engineering-Guide

Flutter Clean Architecture - Template

Noa is Al assistant to run on your Frame AR glasses https://github.com/raheelism/flutter-bloc-clean-architecture...

Ebook App - Flutter

Noa is Al assistant to run on your Frame AR glasses https://github.com/raheelism/Flutter-ebook-app

Flutter ChatGPT

Noa is Al assistant to run on your Frame AR glasses https://github.com/raheelism/flutter_chatgpt

PROJECTS View More

PLEX PDP CARE - Carer App

A Care app for Plex Diagnostic Hospital https://plex-medical.com/

VIDOWN - Download Any Video

A video downloader app built in native android. https://apkpure.com/vidown-video-downloader

SNAPIT- Photo Editor, Meme Maker

A photo editor app built in native android. https://apkpure.com/snapit-photo-editor

LUCKY WHEELER - Try Your Luck

A earning mobile game in native android. https://apkpure.com/lucky-wheeler-try-your-luck

COURSELY - Online Courses

A students learning resources app in flutter. https://apkpure.com/coursely-online-learning

Comply E-Forms

A tax documents and associated eforms app com.complyexchange.ix

UMAVOICE - One Voice, Endless Communication

A Modern AAC app for people with disabilities. https://www.umavoice.com/

VIDED - Video Editor ToolBox

A video editor app built in native android. https://apkpure.com/vided-video-editor-toolbox

INSHORT QUIZ - Exam Preparation

A complete Quiz application developed in Flutter. https://apkpure.com/inshort-quiz-online-game

SCHOLARLY - Scholarship Portal

A students scholarship portal mobile app in flutter. https://apkpure.com/scholarly-scholarship-portal

Spectra Scientific - Water Quality check

A app in flutter to check water quality https://www.spectrascientific.com/

Saaz - Music Application

A music application built in flutter. link is not available